MacKaye Family papers ML-5
Rauner Special Collections Library
- Addendum 3, 1873-1973; 25
  - Posters announcing the St. Louis Pageant and Masque given in celebration of 150th anniversary of..., 1914-1920s (Box 373)
    Posters announcing the St. Louis Pageant and Masque given in celebration of 150th anniversary of the founding of St. Louis (1914); print of peace setting for suffrage allegory by Percy; poster of poem by Walt Whitman (1919); posters with designs by Robert Edmund Jones for "The Roll Call" (1918); community service photo calendar; design of an outer structure for a set design; charcoal caricature of Percy MacKaye by Montgomery Flagg; painting of unidentified woman; painting of "The Grand Pavilion in the Green Park" published Aug. 12, 1814 from Booby London (1919)
- Addendum 4, 1884-1999; 26
  Contains correspondence, writings, clippings, notes, sketches and drawings, photographs, negatives and glass plate negatives related to members of the Mackaye family including Christy MacKaye Barnes, Percy Mackaye, Benton MacKaye, William Payson MacKaye and Robert Keith MacKaye.
  - Steele MacKaye, Mary Medbery MacKay, William Payson MacKaye, Marion Morse Mackaye, Percy MacKaye..., 1884-1999 (Box 374)
    Steele MacKaye, Mary Medbery MacKay, William Payson MacKaye, Marion Morse Mackaye, Percy MacKaye, Benton Mackaye, Christy (MacKaye) Barnes
    - Steele MacKaye: Article in "Theatre Arts Monthly," November, 1927 (Box 374, Folder 1)
    - Steele Mackaye: Photographs, undated (Box 374, Folder 2)
    - Mary Medbery MacKaye: Correspondence, 1889-1919 (Box 374, Folder 3)
    - Mary Medbery MacKaye: "James Knowles Medbery," in "Brown Alumni Magazine", 1913 (Box 374, Folder 4)
    - Mary Medbery MacKaye: "What the Wood-Fire Sang to the Child," poem by Mary Mebdery MacKaye, undated (Box 374, Folder 5)
    - William Payson MacKaye: Pencil Sketches, 1884 (Box 374, Folder 6)
    - James MacKaye: "An Outline of Political Engineering," by James MacKaye, undated (Box 374, Folder 7)
    - Marion Morse MacKaye: Correspondence: Letters to Christy and Arvia Mackaye, 1938 (Box 374, Folder 8)
    - Marion Morse MacKaye: Booklet with watercolors, undated (Box 374, Folder 9)
    - Marion Morse MacKaye: Photographs, undated (Box 374, Folder 10)
    - Marion Morse MacKaye: Speech by Albert Steffen at her memorial, 1939 (Box 374, Folder 11)
    - Marion Morse MacKaye: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 374, Folder 12)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence, 1918-1950 (Box 374, Folder 13)
    - Percy MacKaye:Correspondence: E.A. Robinson (some transcripts), 1930-1934 (Box 374, Folder 14)
    - Percy MacKaye:Correspondence: Sir Oliver Lodge, 1935 (Box 374, Folder 15)
    - Percy MacKaye:Correspondence: Lewis M. Isaacs, 1935 (Box 374, Folder 16)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence: Wright Kramer (some transcripts), 1935 (Box 374, Folder 17)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence: Joseph S. Ford (transcripts 1894-1935), undated (Box 374, Folder 18)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence: US Department of the Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1933 (Box 374, Folder 19)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence: Christy Barnes, 1948 (Box 374, Folder 20)
    - Percy MacKaye: "Untamed America," by Percy MacKaye, undated (Box 374, Folder 21)
    - Percy MacKaye: "The Poetry Society Yearbook 1927-1928," Marquette University (Box 374, Folder 22)
    - Percy MacKaye: "The Returning-James Russell Lowell," by Percy MacKaye, undated (Box 374, Folder 23)
    - Percy MacKaye: Clippings: Poems and reviews, 1948-1950 (Box 374, Folder 24)
    - Percy MacKaye: List of copyrights and renewal dates, undated (Box 374, Folder 25)
    - Percy MacKaye: "Stories of Solomon Shell-The Deer Snowball," with notes, undated (Box 374, Folder 26)
    - Percy MacKaye: Items found in Percy's copy of "Epoch", 1932-1954 (Box 374, Folder 27)
    - Percy MacKaye: "Three Dance Motives," by Percy MacKaye, undated (Box 374, Folder 28)
    - Percy MacKaye: Selected "Last Poems to Christy Barnes", undated (Box 374, Folder 29)
    - Percy MacKaye: Poems, 1956-1968 (Box 374, Folder 30)
    - Percy MacKaye: Flyer: "Hamlet," at Pasadena Playhouse, 1949 (Box 374, Folder 31)
    - Percy MacKaye: "The Shakespeare Association Bulletin", 1949 (Box 374, Folder 32)
    - Percy MacKaye: Poems rejected by Crown Publishers with letter to Christy Barnes, 1969 (Box 374, Folder 33)
    - Percy MacKaye: "Song of the World's Adventures," libretto, words by Percy Mackaye, undated (Box 374, Folder 34)
    - Percy MacKaye: Photographs: Percy and family, undated (Box 374, Folder 35)
    - Percy MacKaye: Photographs: Photo album of Percy and Marion's honeymoon, 1898 (Box 374, Folder 36)
    - Percy MacKaye: Photographs: "Masque of Saint Louis," behind the scenes with correspondence, 1914 (Box 374, Folder 37)
    - Percy MacKaye: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 374, Folder 38)
    - Benton MacKaye: Correspondence: Christy MacKaye, 1956-1966 (Box 374, Folder 39)
    - Benton MacKaye: Correspondence: Christy MacKaye, 1967-1972 (Box 374, Folder 40)
    - Benton MacKaye: Correspondence, 1965 (Box 374, Folder 41)
    - Benton MacKaye: Notes on family reunion of 1916 with photograph (Box 374, Folder 42)
    - Benton MacKaye: "Survey Graphic", 1924 (Box 374, Folder 43)
    - Benton MacKaye: Personal financial papers, 1965-1977 (Box 374, Folder 44)
    - Benton MacKaye: Obituary and related material with correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 374, Folder 45)
    - Benton MacKaye: The Wilderness Society with correspondence, 1976 (Box 374, Folder 46)
    - Benton MacKaye: "Benton MacKaye-Father of the Appalachian Trail," in "The Lowell Sun", 1969 (Box 374, Folder 47)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: Margaret Fuler, 1947 (Box 374, Folder 48)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: The Bond Wheelwright Company, publishers, 1957 (Box 374, Folder 49)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence, 1958-1975 (Box 374, Folder 50)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence regarding Percy MacKaye with other material, 1971-1976 (Box 374, Folder 51)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence regarding Benton MacKaye, 1971-1999 (Box 374, Folder 52)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence regarding "Hamlet-Tetralogy", 1972-1973 (Box 374, Folder 53)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: Fort Hill Players regarding "The Scarecrow," with typescript songs and contracts, 1974-1977 (Box 374, Folder 54)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence regarding "Scarecrow" sketches, 1975 (Box 374, Folder 55)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence regarding "The Scarecrow" performances, with other material, 1975-1979 (Box 374, Folder 56)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: Kennedy Center regarding rights and royalties from "The Scarecrow", 1975 (Box 374, Folder 57)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: Mary (unidentified), 1975-1995 (Box 374, Folder 58)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: Sotheby Parke Bernet, with receipts, 1976 (Box 374, Folder 59)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: Lucy (unidentified), 1976 (Box 374, Folder 60)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: John Hollowitz regarding research on Steele MacKaye's inventions, 1981-1983 (Box 374, Folder 61)
    - Christy Barnes: Correspondence: Hazel MacKaye, 1986 (Box 374, Folder 62)
  - Christy (MacKaye) Barnes, Ariva MacKaye, Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye, 1920-1988 (Box 375)
    Christy (MacKaye) Barnes, Ariva MacKaye, Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye
    - Christy Barnes: "Wind in the Grass-A Book of Poems," by Christy MacKaye, reviews and comments, 1930-1934 (Box 375, Folder 1)
    - Christy Barnes: Poems and writings on the occasion of her marriage to Henry Barnes, 1939 (Box 375, Folder 2)
    - Arvia MacKaye: Correspondence and prospectus regarding revival of Percy's plays by David Butler, 1975 (Box 375, Folder 3)
    - Arvia MacKaye: Miscellaneous, 1938-1973 (Box 375, Folder 4)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Letters from Arvia MacKaye, 1920-1941 (Box 375, Folder 5)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Letters from Christy Mackaye Barnes, 1920-1941 (Box 375, Folder 6)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Letters from Margaret (unidentified), 1920 (Box 375, Folder 7)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Letters from his mother Marion Morse MacKaye, 1920 (Box 375, Folder 9)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Letters from Margaret (unidentified), 1920 (Box 375, Folder 8)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Elizabeth Ford Holt, Camp Mowglis, 1920 (Box 375, Folder 10)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Percy MacKaye, 1920 (Box 375, Folder 11)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Lavenia MacKaye circa 1923 (transcripts), undated (Box 375, Folder 14)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Transcribed letters, 1924-1929, before marriage, bound, undated (Box 375, Folder 15)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Percy Mackaye, 1930-1946 (Box 375, Folder 12)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Percy MacKaye, 1941 (Box 375, Folder 13)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Postcards, 1933-1934 (Box 375, Folder 16)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Letter to Robin and Arvia Mackaye (filed together), 1936 (Box 375, Folder 17)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Anna Goudschaal, some in German, 1938-1941 (Box 375, Folder 18)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence, 1939 (Box 375, Folder 19)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Sanatorium Wiesneck with brochure, 1939 (Box 375, Folder 20)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Jack Gardner, 1939-1941 (Box 375, Folder 21)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence: Letters to Christy, Arvia and Henry, 1941 (Box 375, Folder 22)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence, 1925-1972 (Box 375, Folder 23)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 375, Folder 24)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Photographs: Robin and family including portraits, 1932-1939 (Box 375, Folder 25)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Photographs: Booklets with annotated photos sent as greetings, 1933 (Box 375, Folder 26)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Poem collection, loosely bound (MBL + LMB), 1922 (Box 375, Folder 27)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Material for plays, 1931-1935 (Box 375, Folder 28)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Wings for Hands," by Keith Mackaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 29)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Wings for Hands," by Keith Mackaye, reviews, undated (Box 375, Folder 30)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "The Beetle," by Keith MacKaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 31)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Sketches: "Unger", undated (Box 375, Folder 32)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Notes and remarks by Robert Keith MacKaye, from Drama 40 notes, Yale University Theater, 1929 (Box 375, Folder 33)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Paradox," by Keith MacKaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 34)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "The Smile of MacMillan," by Keith MacKaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 35)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Play Plasms," by Keith MacKaye, 1934 (Box 375, Folder 36)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Hi & I", undated (Box 375, Folder 37)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Outline notes for plays, undated (Box 375, Folder 38)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Man and Animal," translated by Robert Keith Mackaye and Anna Goudschaal ("Mensch und Tier," by Dr. Herman Poppelbaum), 1937 (Box 375, Folder 39)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Itininary-Heimdahl Stockmar and Robert Keith MacKaye, bound, 1938 (Box 375, Folder 40)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "The Swamp," by Robert Keith Mackaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 41)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "The President," by Robert Keith Mackaye, outline, 1927 (Box 375, Folder 42)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Outlines for plays, undated (Box 375, Folder 43)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Fresh-An One Act Play," by Robert Keith Mackaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 44)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Environment-A Essay," by Robert Keith MacKaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 45)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Costume-An Essay," by Robert Keith Mackaye, undated (Box 375, Folder 46)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Outline of play in three acts, undated (Box 375, Folder 47)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "A One Acter", undated (Box 375, Folder 48)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Various writings, undated (Box 375, Folder 49)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Omnivariant Integralism", undated (Box 375, Folder 50)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Kentucky," notes, undated (Box 375, Folder 51)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Humor-First Class," The Great Black Pipe, undated (Box 375, Folder 52)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Robert's translation of Grohman Botany, undated (Box 375, Folder 53)
  - Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye, Hazel MacKaye, Peggy MacKaye and other family members, 1932-1986 (Box 376)
    Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye, Hazel MacKaye, Peggy MacKaye and other family members
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Miscellaneous poems, undated (Box 376, Folder 1)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Miscellaneous stories, undated (Box 376, Folder 2)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Miscellaneous writings and notes, undated (Box 376, Folder 3)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Miscellaneous poems and other writings, undated (Box 376, Folder 4)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Personal Dramatic Analysis, undated (Box 376, Folder 5)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Memories of the Moon," by Keith MacKaye, undated (Box 376, Folder 6)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Out Creative Self (Vitoyf)," by Keith MacKaye, Part I, undated (Box 376, Folder 7)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Out Creative Self (Vitoyf)," by Keith MacKaye, Part II and III, undated (Box 376, Folder 8)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Out Creative Self (Vitoyf)," by Keith MacKaye, undated (Box 376, Folder 9)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Antedeluvian Evolution", undated (Box 376, Folder 10)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: Children, undated (Box 376, Folder 11)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Small Springback," Act One, undated (Box 376, Folder 12)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Small Springback," Act Two, undated (Box 376, Folder 13)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Big Springback", undated (Box 376, Folder 14)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Humor", undated (Box 376, Folder 15)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Honey Holler," by Robert Keith MacKaye, unused, undated (Box 376, Folder 16)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Honey Holler," by Robert Keith MacKaye, German translation, undated (Box 376, Folder 17)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Writings: "Sky Scouts," libretto, words by R. MacKaye, undated (Box 376, Folder 18)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Comment on "Wings of Hands" by others, undated (Box 376, Folder 19)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Drawings by Robert Keith MacKaye, undated (Box 376, Folder 20)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 376, Folder 21)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Bound collection of magazines, notes and writings, 1986 (Box 376, Folder 22)
    - Hazel MacKaye: Photographs: Cabinet cards and photographs, undated (Box 376, Folder 23)
    - Peggy Mackaye: Photographs: Photo album pages, Cornish, NH, undated (Box 376, Folder 24)
    - MacKaye family: Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 376, Folder 25)
    - MacKaye family: Miscellaneous negatives, undated (Box 376, Folder 26)
    - MacKaye family: Correspondence: Tom Wolfe (1933, transcribed) with flyer, undated (Box 376, Folder 27)
    - MacKaye family: "The Duchess of Florence", undated (Box 376, Folder 28)
    - MacKaye family: Ephemera, undated (Box 376, Folder 29)
    - MacKaye family: "Annals of an Era," by Percy MacKaye with dedication to Robert Keith MacKaye and annotations, 1932 (Box 376, Folder 30)
  - Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye: Composition and other notebooks, undated (Box 377)
    Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye: Composition and other notebooks
  - Steele Mackaye, Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye, William Payson Mackaye, Marion Morse MacKaye, Perc..., undated (Box 378)
    Steele Mackaye, Robert (Robin) Keith MacKaye, William Payson Mackaye, Marion Morse MacKaye, Percy MacKaye
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 1)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 2)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 3)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 4)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 5)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 6)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 7)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 8)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 9)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 10)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 11)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 12)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 13)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 14)
    - Steele Mackaye: Oil painting (France?), undated (Box 378, Folder 15)
    - Robert Keith MacKaye: Sketches for costumes, undated (Box 378, Folder 16)
    - William Payson Mackaye: Sketchbook, undated (Box 378, Folder 17)
    - Marion Morse Mackaye: Photograph, dry mounted, undated (Box 378, Folder 18)
    - Percy MacKaye: Photographs by Harris & Ewing, undated (Box 378, Folder 19)
    - Percy MacKaye: Photographs, dry mounted, undated (Box 378, Folder 20)
    - Percy MacKaye: Photo album: "Percy MacKaye at the Players Club," photographed by Ottmar, undated (Box 378, Folder 34)
  - Percy MacKaye: "Caliban" at Harvard, glass plate negatives; Marion Morse MacKaye: Copperplate ph..., undated (Box 379)
    Percy MacKaye: "Caliban" at Harvard, glass plate negatives; Marion Morse MacKaye: Copperplate photogravure block
- Addendum 5, 1870-1998; 27
  July 2014 accession
  - Photographs, letters, and theatre programs. Correspondents include Edgar Lee Masters, Oscar Wild..., 1870-1998 (Box 380)
    Photographs, letters, and theatre programs. Correspondents include Edgar Lee Masters, Oscar Wilde, Edwin A. Robinson, Lewis Mumford, Charles M. Garnier, Vachel Lindsay and Gordon Craig. Includes autographs of Thomas Jefferson, Edwin Markham, Roald Amundsen and Jack London.